<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Apache Kyuubi</title><link>https://kyuubi.apache.org/</link><description>Recent content on Apache Kyuubi</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © 2021-{year}</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kyuubi.apache.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apache Kyuubi(Incubating) 1.4.1-incubating Release Notes</title><link>https://kyuubi.apache.org/release/1.4.1-incubating.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kyuubi.apache.org/release/1.4.1-incubating.html</guid><description>Hi all,
Apache Kyuubi (Incubating) 1.4.1-incubating is now released. It is a maintenance release containing stability fixes which is based on branch-1.4. Mainly fix some issues of the event log.
Apache Kyuubi (Incubating) is a distributed multi-tenant JDBC server for large-scale data processing and analytics, built on top of Apache Spark and designed to support more engines (i.e. Apache Flink). Please refer to Apache Kyuubi (Incubating) to learn more.
To download Apache Kyuubi (Incubating) 1.</description></item><item><title>Apache Kyuubi(Incubating) 1.4.1-incubating released</title><link>https://kyuubi.apache.org/news/2022-01-31-release-1.4.1-incubating.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kyuubi.apache.org/news/2022-01-31-release-1.4.1-incubating.html</guid><description>We are happy to announce the availability of Apache Kyuubi(Incubating) 1.4.1-incubating! Visit the release notes to read about the new features, or download the released today.</description></item><item><title>Apache Kyuubi(Incubating) 1.4.0-incubating Release Notes</title><link>https://kyuubi.apache.org/release/1.4.0-incubating.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kyuubi.apache.org/release/1.4.0-incubating.html</guid><description>Hi all,
In this release, Kyuubi supports the latest Spark 3.2, Z-Order to optimize sql, long running SQL engine without principal and keytab provided, mysql protocol frontend and mysql client. Other major updates includes GROUP engine.share.level support, asynchronous opening session, user-friendly kyuubi beeline and zookeeper authentication enhancement.
To download Apache Kyuubi (Incubating) 1.4.0-incubating, visit the downloads page.
Highlight Fully verified with the latest Spark 3.2
Support Z-Order to optimize SQL</description></item><item><title>Apache Kyuubi(Incubating) 1.4.0-incubating released</title><link>https://kyuubi.apache.org/news/2021-12-10-release-1.4.0-incubating.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kyuubi.apache.org/news/2021-12-10-release-1.4.0-incubating.html</guid><description>We are happy to announce the availability of Apache Kyuubi(Incubating) 1.4.0-incubating! Visit the release notes to read about the new features, or download the released today.</description></item><item><title>Apache Kyuubi(Incubating) 1.3.1-incubating Release Notes</title><link>https://kyuubi.apache.org/release/1.3.1-incubating.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kyuubi.apache.org/release/1.3.1-incubating.html</guid><description>Hi all,
Apache Kyuubi (Incubating) 1.3.1-incubating is now released. It is a maintenance release containing stability fixes which is based on branch-1.3. Mainly fix some issues of the event log.
Apache Kyuubi (Incubating) is a distributed multi-tenant JDBC server for large-scale data processing and analytics, built on top of Apache Spark and designed to support more engines (i.e. Apache Flink). Please refer to Apache Kyuubi (Incubating) to learn more.
To download Apache Kyuubi (Incubating) 1.</description></item><item><title>Apache Kyuubi(Incubating) 1.3.1-incubating released</title><link>https://kyuubi.apache.org/news/2021-10-25-release-1.3.1-incubating.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kyuubi.apache.org/news/2021-10-25-release-1.3.1-incubating.html</guid><description>We are happy to announce the availability of Apache Kyuubi(Incubating) 1.3.1-incubating! Visit the release notes to read about the new features, or download the released today.</description></item><item><title>Apache Kyuubi(Incubating) 1.3.0-incubating Release Notes</title><link>https://kyuubi.apache.org/release/1.3.0-incubating.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kyuubi.apache.org/release/1.3.0-incubating.html</guid><description>To download Apache Kyuubi (Incubating) 1.3.0-incubating, visit the downloads page.
Highlight Fully verified with the latest Spark 3.0/3.1
Support build on JDK8(default), JDK11
Provide enhanced AQE in Kyuubi Spark Extensions (for Spark 3.1)
Provide several auxiliary SQL functions as a supplement to Spark&amp;rsquo;s built-in Functions
Major improvements of Spark on Kubernetes, include documents, integration tests, tools, etc.
Support engine/session level configurable initialize SQL statements</description></item><item><title>Apache Kyuubi(Incubating) 1.3.0-incubating released</title><link>https://kyuubi.apache.org/news/2021-09-14-release-1.3.0-incubating.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kyuubi.apache.org/news/2021-09-14-release-1.3.0-incubating.html</guid><description>We are happy to announce the availability of Apache Kyuubi(Incubating) 1.3.0-incubating! Visit the release notes to read about the new features, or download the released today.</description></item><item><title>Accept Kyuubi into Apache Incubator</title><link>https://kyuubi.apache.org/news/2021-06-21-accept-incubator.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kyuubi.apache.org/news/2021-06-21-accept-incubator.html</guid><description>Kyuubi is accepted into Apache Incubator, see details in incubation status.</description></item><item><title>Apache Kyuubi Releases</title><link>https://kyuubi.apache.org/releases.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kyuubi.apache.org/releases.html</guid><description>License The software licensed under Apache License 2.0.</description></item><item><title>Become A Committer of Apache Kyuubi</title><link>https://kyuubi.apache.org/become_committer.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kyuubi.apache.org/become_committer.html</guid><description>Anyone being supportive of the community and working in any of the CoPDoC areas can become an Apache Kyuubi committer. The CoPDoC is an acronym from ASF to describe how we recognize your contributions not only by code.
Community - You can join us via our mailing list, issue trackers, discussions page to interact with community members, and share vision and knowledge Project - a clear vision and consensus are needed Documentation - without it, the stuff remains only in the minds of the authors Code - discussion goes nowhere without code Apache Kyuubi community strives to be meritocratic.</description></item><item><title>Description</title><link>https://kyuubi.apache.org/description.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kyuubi.apache.org/description.html</guid><description>Apache Kyuubi (Incubating)
Kyuubi is a distributed multi-tenant Thrift JDBC/ODBC server for large-scale data management, processing, and analytics, built on top of Apache Spark and designed to support more engines (i.e., Flink).</description></item><item><title>Guide for Pull Requests</title><link>https://kyuubi.apache.org/pull_request.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kyuubi.apache.org/pull_request.html</guid><description>Review pull requests Kyuubi encourage to help review pull requests of other developers which makes code more robust. The review guide can see Google’s Engineering Practices documentation.
Submit your pull requests Before Before proceeding, it&amp;rsquo;s better to search the issues and pull requests history first. Likely, the problem or request has been discussed.
After checking, you can create a new issue to describe what want to do, and about issues, we have rich types to choose, see here.</description></item><item><title>Issue Tracker</title><link>https://kyuubi.apache.org/issue_tracking.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kyuubi.apache.org/issue_tracking.html</guid><description>The Kyuubi community uses Github Issues to track various ideas, work, bugs, etc. The Github issues tracker integrated with our development repository makes it easier to organize work, focus on essential tasks, and keep plans up to date simultaneously.
Although everyone can create an issue that might include any content as long as you have a Github account and we do not make any mandatory restrictions on the functionality of this section, all communication is subject to the ASF Code of Conduct.</description></item><item><title>Kyuubi Mailing Lists</title><link>https://kyuubi.apache.org/mailing_lists.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kyuubi.apache.org/mailing_lists.html</guid><description>The Kyuubi developer mailing list is the preferred means for all your questions when using Kyuubi, which pushes your doubts out to the entire community. This is the best way to keep up-to-date with the community.
Before you post anything to the mailing lists, be sure that you already subscribe to them. The currently available lists are listed in the below table.
List Name Address Subscribe Unsubscribe Archive Usages Developer List dev@kyuubi.</description></item><item><title>Kyuubi Project Improvement Proposals (KPIP)</title><link>https://kyuubi.apache.org/improvement-proposals.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kyuubi.apache.org/improvement-proposals.html</guid><description>The purpose of a KBIP is to inform and involve the user community in significant improvements to the Kyuubi codebase throughout the development process to increase user needs.
KBIPs should be used for significant user-facing or cross-cutting changes, not minor incremental improvements. When in doubt, if a committer thinks a change needs a KBIP, it does.
What is a KBIP? A KBIP is similar to a product requirement document commonly used in product management.</description></item><item><title>Kyuubi Usage</title><link>https://kyuubi.apache.org/usage.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kyuubi.apache.org/usage.html</guid><description>Kyuubi provides a pure SQL gateway through Thrift JDBC/ODBC interface for end-users to manipulate large-scale data with pre-programmed and extensible Spark SQL engines.
We are aiming to make Kyuubi an &amp;ldquo;out-of-the-box&amp;rdquo; tool for data warehouses and data lakes.
This &amp;ldquo;out-of-the-box&amp;rdquo; model minimizes the barriers and costs for end-users to use Spark at the client side.
At the server-side, Kyuubi server and engines' multi-tenant architecture provides the administrators a way to achieve computing resource isolation, data security, high availability, high client concurrency, etc.</description></item><item><title>Kyuubi Version Control System</title><link>https://kyuubi.apache.org/version_control.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kyuubi.apache.org/version_control.html</guid><description>Overview The Kyuubi source code resides in the Apache git repository, and available from here: https://gitbox.apache.org/repos/asf?p=incubator-kyuubi.git
The changes are also mirrored to the github repository https://github.com/apache/incubator-kyuubi</description></item><item><title>Privacy</title><link>https://kyuubi.apache.org/privacy_policy.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kyuubi.apache.org/privacy_policy.html</guid><description>Information about your use of this website is collected using server access logs and a tracking cookie. The collected information consists of the following:
The IP address from which you access the website; The type of browser and operating system you use to access our site; The date and time you access our site; The pages you visit; and The addresses of pages from where you followed a link to our site.</description></item><item><title>The Kyuubi Ecosystem (present and future)</title><link>https://kyuubi.apache.org/ecosystems.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kyuubi.apache.org/ecosystems.html</guid><description>The figure below shows our vision for the Kyuubi Ecosystem. Some of them have been realized, some in development, and others would not be possible without your help.</description></item><item><title>Useful Developer Tools</title><link>https://kyuubi.apache.org/developer-tools.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kyuubi.apache.org/developer-tools.html</guid><description>Building Kyuubi Building Kyuubi with Apache Maven Kyuubi is built based on Apache Maven,
./build/mvn clean package -DskipTests This results in the creation of all sub-modules of Kyuubi project without running any unit test.
If you want to test it manually, you can start Kyuubi directly from the Kyuubi project root by running
bin/kyuubi start Building a Submodule Individually For instance, you can build the Kyuubi Common module using:
build/mvn clean package -pl :kyuubi-common -DskipTests Building Submodules Individually For instance, you can build the Kyuubi Common module using:</description></item></channel></rss>